Finding Aid for Janet Good Papers, 1965-1996
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Janet Good papers 1965-1996
Good, Janet.
0.5 linear ft.
9638 Aa 2
Feminist, member of the Michigan Employment Security Commission, member of numerous feminist and civil rights organizations. Biographical information; subject files relating to activities with the Older Women's League, the National Organization for Women, and other feminist organizations.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Janet Good (Donor No. 8480 ) on May 21, 1996.
The collection is open to research.
Civil rights activist Janet Good of Farmington Hills, Michigan, is a respected advocate for minorities, the economically disadvantaged, and the aging, and is particularly known for her involvement in the feminist movement. Good served for 25 years with the Michigan Employment Security Commission (MESC), rising to the position of Equal Employment Opportunity Officer before her retirement in 1990. She co-chaired the Governor's Task Force on Sexual Harassment in the Workplace and participated in several capacities in Michigan's 1977 International Women's Year activities.
Good became active in the feminist movement in the 1960s. Her tireless efforts for women's rights earned her the 1981 "Feminist of the Year Award" from the Detroit chapter of the National Organization for Women (NOW). She has been particularly influential in the Older Women's League (OWL), serving on its national board (1984-1987, three years as Secretary), founding its Michigan Federation, and organizing 15 local chapters throughout the state. In addition, Good has been involved in numerous other feminist and civil rights organizations, including NOW, Catholics for a Free Choice, the Michigan Women's Commission, the Michigan Women's Assembly, ERAmerica, the Detroit Human Rights Commission, and the Detroit Gray Panthers. Because of her experience and expertise, she has often been asked to speak at conferences and meetings. In 1991 she was presented with the Michigan Women's Hall of Fame Life Achievement Award.
The papers of Janet Good consist of 0.5 linear feet of documents relating primarily to Good's activities in feminist organizations and her work for the MESC. The papers are organized into a single topical series, arranged alphabetically. With the exception of the Biographical, the bulk of the collection relates to organizations in which Good participated.
The Biographical files documents aspects of Good's career not specifically relating to her involvement in feminist and civil rights organizations. Concise information about Good's life and career is contained in the News Clippings, Resume, and Photograph file.
Files for the National Organization for Women and the Older Women's League. contain materials relating to state or local chapters and to Good's participation on the national level, such as her role in organizing the 1977 NOW National Conference in Detroit and her preparation of Executive Committee minutes for the National Owl Board during her term as Secretary.
Subjects:
Good, Janet.; Feminists--Michigan.; National Organization for Women. Michigan Conference.; Older Women's League (U.S.). Michigan Chapter.
- Topical Files
  - Biographical
    - Awards, 1977-1986 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1989 (Box 1)
    - Employment, 1965-1989 (Box 1)
      (includes photographic negatives)
    - News clippings, resumes, and photograph, 1982-1991 (Box 1)
    - Speeches, reports, and presentations, 1979-1986 (Box 1)
  - Catholics for a Free Choice, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
  - International Women's Year Committee (of the Michigan Employment Security Commission), 1975 (Box 1)
  - Michigan feminist organizations (miscellaneous)
    - Direct involvement by Good, 1975-1989 (Box 1)
    - Less direct involvement by Good, 1987-1990 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Task Force on Sexual Harassment in the Workplace, 1978-1989 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Women's Commission, 1978-1986 (Box 1)
  - National Organization for Women (NOW)
    - Michigan, local chapters, 1975-1989 (Box 1)
    - Michigan, state, 1976-1986 (Box 1)
    - National Conference (Detroit, 1977), 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Older Women's League (OWL)
    - Michigan Federation
      - Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 1981-1986 (Box 1)
      - Newsletters and clippings, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
    - Michigan, local chapters, 1981-1986 (Box 1)
      (includes photographs)
    - National
      - Convention (Detroit, 1989), 1987-1989 (Box 1)
      - Minutes and agendas, 1983-1987 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 1983-1988 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (later accession) (Box 1)